YOHAN ALEX MANFRON

OBJECTIVE: DATA ENGINEERING, TECHNICAL LEADERSHIP

ABOUT ME

Data engineer with twelve years of experience, working as a database administrator, data analyst and data engineer, mostly with transactional databases, SQL, Shell script, transactional SQL, business engagement, agile, and for the past three years, working in leadership roles, as a chapter leader and nowadays as the coordinator for the analytics team.

SKILLS

- Leadership;
- Project management;
- SQL;
- Database Administration (MSSQL, Postgres, MariaDB);
- Business engagement;
- Data pipelines;
- Azure (Data Factory, DW);
- AWS (Glue, S3, Athena, DMS,

Redshift);

- Looker;
- Celonis;
- Shell script;
- Python (junior level);
- Pentaho:
- SAP Data transformation;
- Hana;
- Performance analysis.

EDUCATION

2012 - 2014 IT Management technology - Finished OPET University (Curitiba, PR)

2007 - 2010 Technical formation in IT - High School - Finished Opet High School (Curitiba, PR) Winner of the Project FORMAR, with the best Project of the year 2010.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- **2022–2023** Lojacorr S.A. Insurance company. Job role: Analytics team coordinator
- Main activities: team coordination, technical decision making, data structures creation, data pipeline development, SQL analysis and performance check, Looker dashboard development, with experience in agile and project management.
- **2021–2022** Meta Technology Consulting Company Job role: Data Engineer/Technical Leader.
 - Main activities: Data sets creation, performance analysis, best practices verification, SQL and Database/Performance specialist.
- **2019 2021** ExxonMobil Oil and Energy global company Job role: Data Scientist and Development Consultant.
 - Main activities: Celonis analysis and dashboards development, query analysis, performance analysis and customer engagement.
- **2018 2019** NVL IT Agility Database Consulting Company. Job role: Database Administrator.
 - Main activities: SQL Server and Oracle administration, performance analysis, database, server and storage migration, security configuration, best practices implementation, training, database connection and integration analysis, high availability applications.
- 2016 2018 Lojacorr S.A. Insurance company. Job role: Database Administrator. Main activities: MySQL and SQL Server databases administration, Shell and SQL development. Environment analysis, troubleshooting, database migration, performance and security routines and decision making reports.

YOHAN ALEX MANFRON

IMPORTANT INFORMATION

- Advanced English CCAA (Santa Felicidade) [2006-2011]
- Advanced English Delfin School
 (Dublin Ireland)
- Certifications: IBM Information Management Optim Technical Professional V3 IMPORTANT INFORMATION
- Certifications: Informix System Administration 12.10
- Oracle Administration Training 1 Nerv Informática
- Oracle Administration Training 2 -Nerv Informática
- SQL Server certification Training -Training Education Center
- Celonis Data Engineer Celonis
 Training Center
- Celonis Data Scientist Celonis Training Center
- Celonis Analyst Celonis Training Center
- Celonis Viewer Celonis Training
 Center
- Introdução à Ciencia de de dados Data Scientist Academy Engenharia de dados 2.0 - Data Scientist Academy
- Data Science Academy Python for Data Analysis
 - manfron_yohan@live.com
 - +55 41 9655-9779
 - Rua Jauri Sacks, 343 Cara Cara Ponta Grossa/PR

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- 2012 2016 Horus Informática Database Consulting Company Job Role: Junior database administrator Main activities: Informix database administration, SQL Server database administration, data analysis, shell scripting, SQL scripting, data masking using IBM Optim.
- **2014 2018** CCAA Santa Felicidade Main activities: English teaching for all ages and all levels.
- **2011 2012** HSBC Global Technology Brasil Ltda Main activities: ETL development using IBM Datastage, SQL development, shell scripting, data analysis.